niosdeled.com 2019-06-08

# Privacy Policy | NIOS DelED

if you have any questions or problems regarding the use of your Personal Data and we will gladly assist you.

By using this website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the **Disclaimer**. At http://niosdeled.com/, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by http://NiosDelEd.com/ and how we use it?

**What personal data do we collect NiosDelEd.Com and we collect it**

We strongly encourage you not to share any personal details apart from Your Name and Email ID with us and we may use your Email ID for the newsletter to send notification of our future updates. NiosDelEd.com will never sell any of your data to anyone and we never spam. We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to our newsletter, fill out a form or comment on the site which is used to measure the use of our site and to develop ideas to improve the content of our site. When registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, e-mail address or website URL. You may, however, visit our site anonymously. In general, you can visit NiosDelEd.com Internet sites without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself.

**What do we use your information for?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * **Personalize User experience:** Your information helps us to better respond to visitor needs.
  * **Improve website:** We continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
  * **To improve customer service:** Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs
  * **Send periodic emails:** The email address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
  * Operate our business
  * Understand how users are engaging with niosdeled.com

When visitors leave comments on the site, we collect the data shown in the comments form like Name, Email & URL, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. Cleaning up spam Comment we use Akismet Wordpress plugin, and privacy policy is available here  **https://automattic.com/privacy/**.

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

**Do not share your Personal information in the comment section**

**Information automatically collected about you**

Automatically receive and log certain types of information when you visit or interact with our websites, services, mobile applications or other products, including:

  * Browser Information
  * Operating System Information
  * Mobile Device Information (e.g., device identifier, mobile operating system, etc.)
  * IP Address
  * Internet Service Provider
  * Content Viewed
  * Geographic Location
  * Connection Speed
  * Time of Visit
  * Referring Site, Application, or Service
  * Registration Time

**Children’s Privacy**

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”).

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Information, please contact us. If we discover that a Children under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our servers immediately.

**Log Files**

Like many other Web sites, http://niosdeled.com/ makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and the number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

We do use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

Comment Section – If you leave a comment on our site, you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year. This site using Akismet to reduce spam check How your date proceeds.  **https://automattic.com/privacy-notice/**

Push Notification– niosdeled.com use Onesignal to send the push notifications to our users who opted for it and Onesignal also uses cookies, you can it’s privacy policy here **https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy**

Advertising

  1. Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on http://niosdeled.com/ send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

2) http://niosdeled.com/ has no access or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

3) Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on https://niosdeled.com

4) Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to https://niosdeled.com and other sites on the internet.

5) Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – **https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/**

6) You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers and push notification service for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions on how to opt-out of specific methods. https://niosdeled.com privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.

### Google Adsense

Some of the ads may be served by Google. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to Users based on their visit to our Site and other sites on the Internet. DART uses “non personally identifiable information” and does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, etc. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

Alternatively, you can control some 3rd party cookies by using a privacy enhancement platform such as optout.aboutads.info or youronlinechoices.com. For more information about cookies, visit allaboutcookies.org.

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

**Jetpack Plugin**

We use this plugin for following features check all [privacy policy](https://jetpack.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/?rewind-redirect=%2Fwp-admin%2Fprivacy.php&cta&site=niosdeled.com&u=1#subscriptions) here. Activity Log, Comment Likes, Contact Form, Jetpack Comments, Mobile Theme, Notifications, Protect, Sharing, Subscriptions, WordPress.com Stats,

**Contact forms**

When visitors use any contact forms on the site, we collect their name and email address for a period for customer service purpose, but we do not use the information submitted by through them for marketing purpose.

**Mobile Theme**

Data Used: A visitor’s preference on viewing the mobile version of a site.

Activity Tracked: A cookie (akm_mobile) is stored for 3.5 days to remember whether or not a visitor of the site wishes to view its mobile version. **Learn more about this cookie  **https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#mobile-theme.

**Analytics**

We use Google Analytics to collect user data such as their locations, ISPs etc. You can check Google’s privacy policy here **https://policies.google.com/privacy/update**

**Third Party Links**

We may occasionally, at our discretion, include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We, therefore, have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of those linked sites. We do, however, seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about those sites.

**Online Privacy Policy Only**

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline. By using our site, you consent to our online privacy policy.

**Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**How we secure your data**

We do our best to keep your Personal Data safe. We monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks. Stored data is encrypted when possible. Even though we try our best we can not guarantee the security of information. However, we promise to notify suitable authorities of data breaches.

**How long we retain your data**

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also view and edit that information.

We retain user data from Google analytics for 26 months.

**What rights you have over your data**

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any information you have provided to us. You can also ask that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any info we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

**Where we send your data**

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

**Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## Changes to this privacy policy

http://NiosDelEd.Com has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will send you an email. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

### Your acceptance of these terms

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline. By using our site, you consent to our online privacy policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

Last updated → 26th May 2018

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us

Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content [**network privacy policy**](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). Users from European Union countries may check here at [**Cookies notification**](https://support.google.com/blogger/answer/6253244?p=eu_cookies_notice&hl=en&rd=1)[ **in European Union countries**](https://support.google.com/blogger/answer/6253244?p=eu_cookies_notice&hl=en&rd=1)

  * **Our Hosting Partner   – [Bluehost](http://bluehost.in/)**
